本节中 我们将着重介绍对象捕捉
For this lesson, we're going to covering object snapping particularly.
我们不会介绍地形捕捉或几何捕捉
We won't be covering the actual terrain or geometry snapping,
特别是地形相关操作
specifically to do with the terrain.
我们会介绍这里所展示的例子
We'll be more doing basically as it says right here,
介绍顶点捕捉
cover vertex snapping,
介绍角度捕捉
we'll cover angular snapping,
介绍网格捕捉
and then we'll also cover grip snapping,
我们也有一些例子
and we have little demonstrations
来帮助理解这些概念
to kind of illustrate the point and get us on the same page.
我们开始吧 这样才能理解这些操作的意义
So let's go through them, so that we can understand exactly what we're trying to do.
第一个是顶点捕捉
The first one is vertex snapping,
顶点捕捉会选定一个顶点
with vertex snapping, basically it's going to take a point or a vertice,
将其作为支点与另一个顶点吸附
it's going to snap that as the pivot point to another vertice.
看这个 你就知道我们要做什么了
So if we scroll over here, we can see exactly what we want to do.
我们想让这两点接触
We want to have both of there points touch,
要想这样做 需要打开顶点捕捉
so in order to do so, we need to activate vertex snapping.
选取这个物体 然后看上面这里
Let's grab this designer object, and go up to the top here,
会发现有个“切换至顶点捕捉”
you'll notice that we have "Toggle snapping to vertex".
激活它后
When we activate this,
会看见上面写着“捕捉到顶点” 以及这些点
you'll see it says "Snap to vertex" and we have all these points that pop up.
我们想要做的是选择这个点
We actually want to do is take this point
按住鼠标左键
and holding the left mouse button down,
往下拉 让它捕捉到下面的顶点
we can drag it and snap it to this point.
这样就跟远处的那个一样了
Completely replicating what it seen in the distance.
再点一下按钮 就可以关闭它
So let's go ahead and click again and deactivate it,
这样就成功的用顶点捕捉将两点捕捉在一起
and we've successfully used vertex snapping to snap two points to each other.
接下来这个例子介绍角度捕捉
This next lesson goes over the angular snapping
可以看到这里有30 45 90
which we can see that we have 30, 45 and 90,
来到远处这里
and if we go off to the distance here,
可以看到其呈现出30 45 90度角
we can see that we have the angles of 30, 45 and 90 available to us.
我们想复制这些角度值到另一个物体上
We want to replicate these same angular values of snapping on the other objects.
我们从30这个开始
So to start off, we'll go and grab the 30,
选中这个物体
let's click and select the object,
在上面这里 有角度捕捉按钮
and then up in the top here, we have the angular snapping.
按住鼠标左键不放
Let's click the left mouse button down and hold,
选择30 然后松手
we're gonna select 30.
再点下按钮就会激活它
So it's activated by clicking again,
按2键 可以看见这里有帮助器
press the 2 key, we can notice that we have some helpers here,
可以看见这些间隔是30度
we can see these points are actually 30-degree values.
我们按住Z轴
So if we click and hold down on the Z-axis,
就可以移过去 也就是30度
you can snap it over, so it's 30 degrees.
用同样的方法做下一个 45度
Let's do the same for the other two, so we have 45,
按住
I'm gonna hold down,
选45
pick 45
然后移过去
and snap over.
同样方法 最后一个 90度
And let's do this for the last one in 90,
这样 我们就通过角度捕捉
And now doing so, we've replicated exactly the same thing on the other side
复现了对面的效果
by just going into angular snapping.
关掉它后 来到网格捕捉部分
We're gonna deactivate it, and now we're gonna go to the grid snapping section,
这是挺大的盒子 因为大小单位是米
which is quite larger, I mean this box is for this based on meters,
所以这是4米单位
so that mean it's 4 meters in units.
而这是2米 这是1米
This one's 2, this one's 1,
显然这是0.5米
and then obviously that's 0.5.
而我们想要以远处的这种方式叠放
So in the distance we can see that we wanna stack them in this variety,
我们可以用网格捕捉来做
and we can use grid snapping in order to do so.
先把这个盒子往后移
So let's first move this box back,
我们选择距离增量
we're gonna select the meter increments,
确保是1
make sure it's 1,
再点下图标来激活它
activate with the actual left mouse button clicked
可以看见现在有了距离网格
and we can see that we now have a meter grid up.
把这个往后移 让它保持在平台上
And let's move this to the back here, so we can have it on the same platform
再移一点点
for maybe a little bit over.
我把距离增量降低到0.5
I'm gonna shrink it down to actually 0.5,
这样就能尽可能的压缩空间
so we can scoot it back and have the most area.
这样就放进角落 这也是我想要的效果
So now we kind of have in the corner back here which is exactly what we want.
让我们回到
So let's go back to
2号盒子 往下移动
our number 2, and move this downward,
因为我们要把它放在角落里
because we need to get it over in the corner as well.
移过去
So we move it over,
然后往前移
then we move it forward.
现在2个盒子就位了
We now have 2 boxes in position.
选中1米的盒子往下移
So let's select the one meter box and drag it downward,
这个应该能恰好贴合
this should fit just quite snug.
最后 选中0.5米的盒子
And lastly, we want to pick the 0.5 meter box,
跟距离增量一样 都是0.5米
which is same increment that we have.
我感觉有点偏了
And I actually think this is off slightly,
所以我移动下盒子 以确定贴合的没问题
so I'm gonna select a box and make sure snapping properly.
看起来没有问题了
And it seems to be right in place.
这样我们就复现了同样的效果
So now we've replicated the same meter setup,
包括本集里的网格捕捉 角度捕捉
inside of this lesson that shows here, here with angular
以及顶点捕捉
and then finally with vertex snapping.
以后会介绍其他捕捉 但这集介绍的是针对于物体的
We'll cover the different other types of snapping, but this is specific to objects
也是你最常用的 所以我想从这个最基本的讲起
and you use this quite a lot, so I wanted to cover this in the most basic sense.
翻译：他出院了